<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>technology errors and omissions Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/tag/technology-errors-and-omissions/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/technology-errors-and-omissions/</link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 09:12:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>technology errors and omissions Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/technology-errors-and-omissions/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>How to Prevent Technology Errors and Omissions from Ruining Your System</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/how-to-prevent-technology-errors-and-omissions-from-ruining-your-system/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 08:23:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cyber Security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cyber security]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technology errors and omissions]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you are a system administrator or a developer, you know how important it is to maintain the integrity of your system. Integrity means that the data and the functionality of the system are accurate, consistent, and reliable. However, integrity can be easily compromised by technology errors and omissions, which are the number-one threat to&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/how-to-prevent-technology-errors-and-omissions-from-ruining-your-system/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How to Prevent Technology Errors and Omissions from Ruining Your System</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/how-to-prevent-technology-errors-and-omissions-from-ruining-your-system/">How to Prevent Technology Errors and Omissions from Ruining Your System</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are a system administrator or a developer, you know how important it is to maintain the integrity of your system. Integrity means that the data and the functionality of the system are accurate, consistent, and reliable. However, integrity can be easily compromised by technology errors and omissions, which are the number-one threat to the system.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Save Your System from the Biggest Threat: Yourself</h2>



<div class="wp-block-roelmagdaleno-callout-block"><div class="wp-callout-box__inner-blocks">
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyber_insurance">Errors and omissions</a> are mistakes or oversights that occur when users interact with the system. They can be intentional or unintentional, malicious or benign, but they all have the potential to damage or destroy data, corrupt files, introduce bugs, or cause downtime.</p>
</div></div>



<p>For example, a user might accidentally delete a crucial file, overwrite a configuration setting, enter invalid data, or forget to perform a necessary task. However, if the users intentionally modify the data or destroy the information, it is called an <a href="https://uniqwe.com/cyber-security-how-can-internal-threats-be-prevented/">internal threat</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/brashearsinsurance.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/tech-errors.jpg?fit=2120%2C1414&amp;ssl=1" alt=""/></figure></div>


<p>It is difficult to protect the system from the users who need to use it every day because you cannot simply lock down the system and prevent any changes from happening. So how can you protect your system from technology e&amp;o? Here are some solutions that you can implement to reduce the risk and impact of these common threats:</p>



<ul>
<li>Training: One of the best ways to prevent errors and omissions is to educate your users on how to use the system properly and securely. You should provide clear and comprehensive documentation, tutorials, manuals, and guidelines for your users. You should also conduct regular training sessions and workshops to refresh their knowledge and skills. You should emphasize the importance of following best practices, avoiding common pitfalls, and reporting any issues or anomalies.</li>



<li>Security concept “least privilege”: This means that users should only have access to the minimum amount of data and functions that they need to perform their tasks. This reduces the chances of users making mistakes or abusing their privileges. It also limits the damage that can be done if a user&#8217;s account is compromised by an attacker.</li>



<li>Adequate and frequent backups: Finally, make adequate and frequent backups of the information on the systems. Backups are copies of your data and files that you can use to restore your system when it crashes. You should backup your system regularly and store your backups in a secure location or encrypt them. You should also test your backups periodically to ensure that they are valid and usable.</li>
</ul>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>By implementing these solutions, you can prevent technology errors and omissions from compromising your system integrity. You can also improve your system performance, reliability, and security with an insurance. Remember that errors and omissions are inevitable, but they are not insurmountable. With proper planning, preparation, and prevention, you can protect your system from the users who need to use it every day.</p>



<p>We hope you found this post useful and informative. If you have any questions or comments, please feel free to leave them below. Thank you for reading and stay tuned for more cybersecurity tips!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/how-to-prevent-technology-errors-and-omissions-from-ruining-your-system/">How to Prevent Technology Errors and Omissions from Ruining Your System</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
