<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Database management systems Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/category/database-management-systems/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/category/database-management-systems/</link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:45:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Database management systems Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/category/database-management-systems/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What is a query execution plan?</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database management systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[execution plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[query execution plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A query execution plan is a graphical or textual representation of the steps that the database engine takes to process a query. It provides a blueprint for the DBMS to retrieve data from one or more tables based on the query&#8217;s criteria. In this article, we will delve deeper into what it is, how it&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">What is a query execution plan?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/">What is a query execution plan?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A query execution plan is a graphical or textual representation of the steps that the database engine takes to process a query. It provides a blueprint for the DBMS to retrieve data from one or more tables based on the query&#8217;s criteria. In this article, we will delve deeper into what it is, how it works, and its importance in optimizing query performance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a query execution plan and examples</h2>



<p>When a user submits a query to a DBMS, the optimizer evaluates various execution strategies and selects the most efficient one for the given query. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Query_plan">The execution plan</a> generated by the optimizer includes details such as which indexes will be used, the order in which data will be retrieved, and how the data will be joined together. You can use a query execution plan to answer questions such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>How does the database engine scan or seek the data in the tables or indexes?</li>



<li>What kind of joins does the database engine use to combine data from multiple tables?</li>



<li>How does the database engine sort, group, filter, or aggregate the data?</li>



<li>How does the database engine use temporary storage or memory for intermediate results?</li>



<li>How does the database engine estimate the cost and cardinality of each step in the plan?</li>
</ul>



<p>For example, consider a simple query that retrieves all customer information from a table named &#8220;Customers&#8221; where the customer&#8217;s age is greater than 30. The DBMS optimizer may use an index on the &#8220;age&#8221; column to filter out all customers under 30 years old. It may then join this filtered data with another table containing additional customer information to retrieve the final result set.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://learn.microsoft.com/vi-vn/sql/relational-databases/performance/media/display-an-actual-execution-plan/actualexecplan.png?view=sql-server-2017" alt=""/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Example of a query execution plan in MS SQL Server</figcaption></figure>



<p>The execution plan generated by the optimizer is crucial in ensuring that queries are executed efficiently. Without an execution plan, the DBMS would have to scan through all data in a table to retrieve the required information, which can be time-consuming and resource-intensive.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">To generate and modify a query execution plan</h2>



<p>To generate a query execution plan, you can use tools base on <a href="https://uniqwe.com/category/database-management-systems/">your DBMS</a> such as SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT), or Azure Data Studio (ADS) for SQL Server databases, or Oracle SQL Developer, MySQL Workbench, or pgAdmin for other databases. These tools usually have a graphical interface that allows you to view the plan as a tree or a diagram, where each node represents an operation or an operator. You can also view the plan as a text or XML format that provides more details and statistics.</p>



<p>Furthermore, we can analyze the execution plan to identify performance bottlenecks and optimize query performance. For example, if the optimizer is not using an index that could improve query performance, we can modify the execution plan to include the index.</p>



<p>A query execution plan can be either an estimated plan or an actual plan. An estimated plan is generated before the query is executed and shows what the database engine expects to do based on the statistics and metadata of the tables and indexes. An actual plan is generated after the query is executed and shows what the database engine actually did based on the actual data and resources. An actual plan also includes additional information such as actual row counts, execution time, and wait statistics.</p>



<p>By comparing an estimated plan and an actual plan, you can see if there are any discrepancies between what the database engine expected and what it actually did. For example, if the estimated row count is much lower or higher than the actual row count, it might indicate that the statistics are outdated or inaccurate, which can affect the performance and accuracy of the query. You can also see if there are any warnings or errors in the plan that indicate potential problems such as missing indexes, implicit conversions, parameter sniffing, or memory spills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, a query execution plan is a blueprint that outlines how a DBMS will execute a particular query. A query execution plan is a powerful tool that can help you optimize your queries and improve your database performance. By learning how to read and analyze a query execution plan, you can gain valuable insights into how your queries work and how to make them faster and more efficient.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/">What is a query execution plan?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/techniques-other-than-chaining-to-handle-bucket-overflow/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 16:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database management systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=86</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are some other techniques for dealing with bucket overflow when using external hashing. All of these methods are commonly used in computer science: open addressing or linear probing, quadratic probing, double hashing, and cuckoo hashing. Techniques to handle bucket overflow in external hashing External hashing is a type of hash table that is used&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/techniques-other-than-chaining-to-handle-bucket-overflow/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/techniques-other-than-chaining-to-handle-bucket-overflow/">Techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>There are some other techniques for dealing with bucket overflow when using external hashing. All of these methods are commonly used in computer science: open addressing or linear probing, quadratic probing, double hashing, and cuckoo hashing.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Techniques to handle bucket overflow in external hashing</h2>



<p>External hashing is a type of hash table that is used to store and retrieve data efficiently. In external hashing, a hash function is used to map each key value to an index in an array, which is called a bucket. Each bucket contains one or more records, depending on the size of the record and the size of the bucket. In some cases, it is possible for a bucket to overflow, meaning that there are more records than can fit in the bucket. When this happens, chaining is the most common technique used to handle the overflow. However, other techniques can be employed to handle bucket overflow in external hashing.</p>



<p>We will take a general look at each techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow in external hashing:</p>



<p>1. Open addressing or linear probing: When a collision occurs, the algorithm tries to find the next available slot in the hash table and stores the key-value pairs in that slot. This technique ensures a better cache locality and reduces the number of disk I/O operations.</p>



<p>2. Quadratic probing: This technique is similar to open addressing, but it uses a quadratic sequence to search for an empty slot in the hash table. This reduces the clustering effect that occurs with linear probing.</p>



<p>3. Double hashing: This technique uses two hash functions to determine the next available slot when a collision occurs. One hash function calculates the initial slot, and the other calculates the offset. If the initial slot is already taken, the algorithm adds the offset to the initial slot and checks whether that slot is available.</p>



<p>4. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuckoo_hashing">Cuckoo hashing</a>: This technique uses multiple hash functions and hash tables. When a collision occurs, the algorithm tries to move the conflicting data to the next hash table using one of the hash functions. This process continues until the data is successfully stored or the algorithm reaches the maximum number of iterations.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://www.andrew.cmu.edu/user/bqiu/img/cuckoo.png" alt="" width="354" height="383"/></figure></div>


<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Open addressing or linear probing, quadratic probing, double hashing, and cuckoo hashing.</h2>



<p>All of these techniques are designed to resolve bucket overflow in external hashing without resorting to traditional chaining.</p>



<p>One of the techniques that can be used to handle bucket overflow is called open addressing. In open addressing, when a key value is mapped to a bucket that is already full, the hash function is used to compute a new index that is different from the original index. This process is repeated until an empty bucket is found. The record is then stored in the empty bucket. The advantage of open addressing is that it can lead to faster access times than chaining because there is no need to follow a chain of pointers to find the record.</p>



<p>Another technique that can be used to handle bucket overflow is called linear probing. In linear probing, when a bucket is found to be full, instead of computing a new index and hashing the key again, the hash function is used to find the next available bucket in a linear sequence. The record is then stored in the next available bucket. Linear probing can be faster than chaining because there is no need to follow a chain of pointers, and records are stored in contiguous locations in memory.</p>



<p>A third technique that can be used to handle bucket overflow is called quadratic probing. In quadratic probing, instead of searching for the next bucket in a linear sequence, the hash function is used to compute a new index based on a quadratic function. This technique can help to distribute records more evenly throughout the hash table and reduce the likelihood of collisions.</p>



<p>Finally, a fourth technique that can be used to handle bucket overflow is called double hashing. In double hashing, when a bucket is found to be full, a second hash function is used to compute a new index that is added to the original index. The record is then stored in the new index. The advantage of double hashing is that it can lead to a more even distribution of records throughout the hash table and reduce the likelihood of collisions.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, while chaining is the most common technique used to handle bucket overflow in external hashing, other techniques such as open addressing, linear probing, quadratic probing, and double hashing can also be used. Each technique has its advantages and disadvantages, and the choice of technique should depend on the specific requirements of the application.</p>



<p>This artile has provided you with answers for the question Can you think of techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow. If you have any questions, you can leave us a reply and we will help you soon.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/techniques-other-than-chaining-to-handle-bucket-overflow/">Techniques other than chaining to handle bucket overflow</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file?</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/how-does-multilevel-indexing-improve-the-efficiency-of-searching-an-index-file/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 07:57:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database management systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=68</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In today&#8217;s world, data is everything. It is the backbone of any organization, and access to it is critical for decision-making, analysis, and forecasting. However, as the amount of data grows, so does the complexity of managing it. One of the challenges in managing large amounts of data is indexing, which is the process of&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/how-does-multilevel-indexing-improve-the-efficiency-of-searching-an-index-file/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">How does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/how-does-multilevel-indexing-improve-the-efficiency-of-searching-an-index-file/">How does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In today&#8217;s world, data is everything. It is the backbone of any organization, and access to it is critical for decision-making, analysis, and forecasting. However, as the amount of data grows, so does the complexity of managing it. One of the challenges in managing large amounts of data is indexing, which is the process of organizing data to facilitate quick and efficient access. In this article, we will explore the concept of multilevel indexing and how does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How Does Multilevel Indexing work</h2>



<p>Multilevel indexing is a technique used to break down an index file into smaller, more manageable sections. This technique creates multiple levels of indexes, with each level pointing to a smaller subset of the data. A primary index can be created for the index itself, which is called the second-level index. This process can be repeated to create a third, fourth, and top level until all entries fit in one disk block.</p>



<p>Multilevel <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Database_index">indexing </a>offers several benefits to organizations that need to manage large amounts of data. One of the most significant benefits is faster access to specific data. By breaking down the index file into smaller sections, it is easier to find and retrieve specific information quickly. This can save organizations time and money by reducing the amount of time needed to search through large amounts of data.</p>



<p>Another benefit of multilevel indexing is improved data management. By dividing the index file into smaller sections, it is easier to manage and maintain the data. This can reduce the risk of errors and improve data accuracy. Additionally, multilevel indexing can help organizations scale their data management systems as their needs grow.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">How does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file</h2>



<p><strong>1. Faster Access to Specific Data</strong><br><br>Multilevel indexing allows for faster access to specific data by breaking down the index file into smaller subsets. Each level of the index points to a subset of the data, reducing the amount of time needed to search through large amounts of information. For example, if an organization has a database with millions of records, a multilevel index can be created to divide the records into smaller subsets based on specific criteria such as date, location, or product type. This makes it easier to find and retrieve specific information quickly.<br><br><strong>2. Reduced Search Time</strong><br><br>Multilevel indexing reduces search time by narrowing down the search to a smaller subset of data. Instead of searching through the entire index file, the search is limited to a specific subset of data. This reduces the amount of time needed to search through large amounts of information and improves the efficiency of the search process.<br><br><strong>3. Improved Data Management</strong><br><br>Multilevel indexing improves data management by dividing the index file into smaller sections. This makes it easier to manage and maintain the data, reducing the risk of errors and improving data accuracy. Additionally, multilevel indexing can help organizations scale their data management systems as their needs grow.<br><br><strong>4. Scalability</strong><br><br>Multilevel indexing is scalable, which means it can grow with an organization&#8217;s needs. As an organization&#8217;s data grows, more levels can be added to the index file, allowing for faster access to specific data.<br><br>For example, consider a library catalog that contains thousands of books. Without multilevel indexing, searching for a specific book would require searching through the entire catalog. However, with multilevel indexing, the catalog can be divided into smaller subsets based on specific criteria such as author, title, or subject. This makes it easier to find and retrieve specific books quickly, improving the efficiency of the search process.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>While multilevel indexing offers many benefits, it also comes with some challenges. One of the biggest challenges is inserting or deleting new index entries. Because every level of the index is an ordered file, adding or removing entries can be challenging and time-consuming. Additionally, multilevel indexing requires more than one disk block to obtain the top level fit on one disk block, which can increase storage costs. The data structure usually used to implement indexing in most dbms nowadays are B tree and B+ tree to optimize and reduce the cost of updating entries.</p>



<p>Multilevel indexing is a powerful technique that can help organizations manage large amounts of data more effectively. By breaking down the index file into smaller sections, it is easier to find and retrieve specific information quickly. While there are some challenges associated with multilevel indexing, the benefits outweigh the costs for many organizations. As data continues to play an increasingly important role in business operations, multilevel indexing will become even more critical for managing and accessing information efficiently.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/how-does-multilevel-indexing-improve-the-efficiency-of-searching-an-index-file/">How does multilevel indexing improve the efficiency of searching an index file?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why can we have at most one primary or clustering index ?</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/why-can-we-have-at-most-one-primary-or-clustering-index/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 17:36:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database management systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=65</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the world of database management systems, indexes play a crucial role in optimizing data access and retrieval. An index is a data structure that organizes the records of a file based on one or more fields, allowing faster and more efficient search operations. However, not all indexes are created equal, and some have more&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/why-can-we-have-at-most-one-primary-or-clustering-index/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Why can we have at most one primary or clustering index ?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/why-can-we-have-at-most-one-primary-or-clustering-index/">Why can we have at most one primary or clustering index ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the world of database management systems, indexes play a crucial role in optimizing data access and retrieval. An index is a data structure that organizes the records of a file based on one or more fields, allowing faster and more efficient search operations. However, not all indexes are created equal, and some have more restrictions than others. We are about to discuss the reasons why can we have at most one primary or clustering index on a file, while we can have as many as secondary indexes in this article.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Primary index, clustering index and secondary index</h2>



<p>One of the main distinctions in index types is between primary or clustering indexes and secondary indexes. A primary or clustering index is the main access path to a file, and it determines the physical order of the records in the file. Typically, a primary index is created on the primary key of a table, which is a unique identifier for each record. For example, in a customer database, the primary key could be the customer ID, and the primary index would organize the records based on this field.</p>



<p>On the other hand, a secondary index is an additional access path to a file that does not affect the physical order of the records. Instead, a secondary index points to the location of the records based on a non-primary key field. For instance, in the same customer database, a secondary index could be created on the customer&#8217;s last name, allowing for faster searches by name.</p>



<p>Now, why can we have at most one primary or clustering index on a file, but several secondary indexes? The answer lies in the nature of these indexes and their impact on the file organization. A primary or clustering index is unique because it defines the physical order of the records in the file. When a new record is inserted into the file, it must be placed in its correct position according to the primary key value. If there were multiple primary indexes on different fields, there would be conflicting orders for the same file, making it impossible to maintain consistency.</p>



<p>For example, imagine a sales database with two primary indexes: one on the date of the sale and another on the customer ID. If a new sale record is added, should it be inserted based on its date or its customer ID? The answer depends on which index is used as the primary access path, but having both would create ambiguity and inefficiency.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Why we can have unlimited secondary indexes</h2>



<p>On the other hand, secondary indexes do not affect the physical order of the records. They only provide additional paths to access the data based on different fields. Therefore, it is possible to have several secondary indexes on a file without conflicting with each other or with the primary index.</p>



<p>For instance, going back to our customer database example, we could have secondary indexes on fields such as email address, phone number, city, or any other attribute that users might want to search by. These indexes would not change the order of the records in the file but would speed up queries that use those fields.</p>



<p>In short, the reason for this is that a primary or clustering index determines the physical order of the records in a file, whereas a secondary index only provides an additional path to access the data. Therefore, having multiple primary or clustering indexes would result in conflicting physical orders for the same file, which would be impossible to maintain. On the other hand, several secondary indexes can be created on a file because they do not affect the physical order of the records, but only provide alternative ways to locate them.</p>



<p>Ultimately, having at most one primary or clustering index on a file and several secondary indexes is a fundamental principle of database design. It reflects the importance of maintaining a consistent physical order for the records while providing flexibility in accessing them through different paths. Understanding these differences can help database administrators optimize their systems&#8217; performance and avoid potential conflicts or errors.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/why-can-we-have-at-most-one-primary-or-clustering-index/">Why can we have at most one primary or clustering index ?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
