<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>diamonds Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/tag/diamonds/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link></link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 02:04:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>diamonds Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link></link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Diamonds Rihanna meaning: shine bright like a diamond</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/diamonds-rihanna-meaning-song/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 16:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[diamonds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rihanna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If you love Rihanna&#8217;s songs, you probably know her hit song &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; from her seventh album Unapologetic. But do you know what this song is really about? In this blog post, we will explore the meaning of &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; by Rihanna, and why it is such an empowering and uplifting anthem for anyone who wants to&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/diamonds-rihanna-meaning-song/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Diamonds Rihanna meaning: shine bright like a diamond</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/diamonds-rihanna-meaning-song/">Diamonds Rihanna meaning: shine bright like a diamond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you love Rihanna&#8217;s songs, you probably know her hit song &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; from her seventh album Unapologetic. But do you know what this song is really about? In this blog post, we will explore the meaning of &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; by Rihanna, and why it is such an empowering and uplifting anthem for anyone who wants to shine bright like a diamond.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Who wrote Diamonds song?</h2>



<p>Although many people could be misled that Rihanna wrote the song, &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; was actually written by <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sia">Sia Furler</a>, a talented Australian singer-songwriter who also wrote songs for Christina Aguilera, David Guetta, and many others. Sia reportedly wrote the lyrics in just 14 minutes, using a simple but effective technique: she started with a basic image of diamonds in the sky, and used it as a metaphor for finding the light and happiness in oneself and in a loving relationship. She then supported this theme with other words that rhyme with &#8220;sky&#8221;, such as &#8220;alive&#8221;, &#8220;eyes&#8221;, &#8220;I&#8221;, and so on.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://64.media.tumblr.com/148c7a4117ed4c642224227b6d10fc1e/tumblr_ovh978fwOw1tg054do1_540.png" alt=""/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><font style="vertical-align: inherit;"><font style="vertical-align: inherit;">Sia</font></font></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The song was produced by Stargate and Benny Blanco, who added synthesizers, orchestral sounds, and electronic rhythms to create a mid-tempo pop, electronic, and R&amp;B ballad that contrasts with Rihanna&#8217;s previous songs about unhealthy relationships. Instead of singing about pain, violence, or addiction, Rihanna sings about choosing to be happy, finding beauty in the sea, and feeling like diamonds with her lover. She also references moonshine and molly, which are slang terms for alcohol and ecstasy, suggesting that she is enjoying a euphoric and transcendent experience with her partner</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Diamonds song and music videos</h2>



<p>The song&#8217;s message is one of hope and positivity, as Rihanna told MTV News: &#8220;I think a lot of people are afraid of being happy because of what others might think of it. They&#8217;re afraid to embrace that and embrace themselves and love themselves and do what they love and do what makes them happy. My story is definitely going to be a happily ever after, no matter what.&#8221;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="nv-iframe-embed"><iframe title="Rihanna - Diamonds" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lWA2pjMjpBs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>



<p>The song&#8217;s MV, directed by Anthony Mandler, shows Rihanna in different settings that represent the four elements: earth, air, water, and fire. These symbolize the chaos and destruction that surround her, but also the beauty and power that she possesses. She is seen running from explosions, swimming underwater, lying on a desert floor, and embracing her lover in front of a burning car. The video focuses more on emotion than on narrative, as Rihanna explained: &#8220;With &#8216;Diamonds&#8217;, it was just a series of vignettes that we put together to help get the emotion across throughout the song &#8217;cause the song changes and it builds.&#8221;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is Diamonds Rihanna meaning of song</h2>



<p>Rihanna&#8217;s hit song &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; is a powerful and inspiring anthem that speaks to the human spirit&#8217;s resilience and strength. The song&#8217;s lyrics are full of metaphors that suggest that even in the darkest moments, there is still something beautiful and valuable to hold onto, like a diamond.</p>



<p>The song begins with Rihanna singing, &#8220;Shine bright like a diamond.&#8221; This line sets the tone for the rest of the song, suggesting that even in difficult times, we can still <a href="https://uniqwe.com/every-wall-is-a-door-quote-meaning-ralph-waldo-emerson/">shine and be brilliant</a>. The chorus repeats this phrase, emphasizing the importance of holding onto hope and finding light in the darkness.</p>



<p>The verses of the song touch on themes of love and relationships, suggesting that true love can help us overcome even the toughest challenges. Rihanna sings, &#8220;Find light in the beautiful sea, I choose to be happy. You and I, you and I, we&#8217;re like diamonds in the sky.&#8221; These lines suggest that even when things are tough, we can choose to focus on the good and find happiness.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Summary</h2>



<p>The bridge of the song is particularly powerful, with Rihanna singing, &#8220;I saw the life inside your eyes.&#8221; This line suggests that even when we feel alone or lost, there are people around us who care and see our worth. It&#8217;s a reminder that we are never truly alone and that there is always hope.</p>



<p>Overall, &#8220;Diamonds&#8221; is a song about finding strength and hope in difficult times. It encourages us to find our inner light and let it shine through the darkness. It reminds us that we are all beautiful and precious like diamonds in the sky. The song&#8217;s message is universal and has resonated with listeners around the world, making it one of Rihanna&#8217;s most beloved songs.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/diamonds-rihanna-meaning-song/">Diamonds Rihanna meaning: shine bright like a diamond</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
