<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>execution plan Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/tag/execution-plan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/execution-plan/</link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:45:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>execution plan Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/execution-plan/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>What is a query execution plan?</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 17:20:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Database management systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[execution plan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[query execution plan]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=103</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>A query execution plan is a graphical or textual representation of the steps that the database engine takes to process a query. It provides a blueprint for the DBMS to retrieve data from one or more tables based on the query&#8217;s criteria. In this article, we will delve deeper into what it is, how it&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">What is a query execution plan?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/">What is a query execution plan?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A query execution plan is a graphical or textual representation of the steps that the database engine takes to process a query. It provides a blueprint for the DBMS to retrieve data from one or more tables based on the query&#8217;s criteria. In this article, we will delve deeper into what it is, how it works, and its importance in optimizing query performance.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">What is a query execution plan and examples</h2>



<p>When a user submits a query to a DBMS, the optimizer evaluates various execution strategies and selects the most efficient one for the given query. <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Query_plan">The execution plan</a> generated by the optimizer includes details such as which indexes will be used, the order in which data will be retrieved, and how the data will be joined together. You can use a query execution plan to answer questions such as:</p>



<ul>
<li>How does the database engine scan or seek the data in the tables or indexes?</li>



<li>What kind of joins does the database engine use to combine data from multiple tables?</li>



<li>How does the database engine sort, group, filter, or aggregate the data?</li>



<li>How does the database engine use temporary storage or memory for intermediate results?</li>



<li>How does the database engine estimate the cost and cardinality of each step in the plan?</li>
</ul>



<p>For example, consider a simple query that retrieves all customer information from a table named &#8220;Customers&#8221; where the customer&#8217;s age is greater than 30. The DBMS optimizer may use an index on the &#8220;age&#8221; column to filter out all customers under 30 years old. It may then join this filtered data with another table containing additional customer information to retrieve the final result set.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://learn.microsoft.com/vi-vn/sql/relational-databases/performance/media/display-an-actual-execution-plan/actualexecplan.png?view=sql-server-2017" alt=""/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Example of a query execution plan in MS SQL Server</figcaption></figure>



<p>The execution plan generated by the optimizer is crucial in ensuring that queries are executed efficiently. Without an execution plan, the DBMS would have to scan through all data in a table to retrieve the required information, which can be time-consuming and resource-intensive.&nbsp;</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">To generate and modify a query execution plan</h2>



<p>To generate a query execution plan, you can use tools base on <a href="https://uniqwe.com/category/database-management-systems/">your DBMS</a> such as SQL Server Management Studio (SSMS), SQL Server Data Tools (SSDT), or Azure Data Studio (ADS) for SQL Server databases, or Oracle SQL Developer, MySQL Workbench, or pgAdmin for other databases. These tools usually have a graphical interface that allows you to view the plan as a tree or a diagram, where each node represents an operation or an operator. You can also view the plan as a text or XML format that provides more details and statistics.</p>



<p>Furthermore, we can analyze the execution plan to identify performance bottlenecks and optimize query performance. For example, if the optimizer is not using an index that could improve query performance, we can modify the execution plan to include the index.</p>



<p>A query execution plan can be either an estimated plan or an actual plan. An estimated plan is generated before the query is executed and shows what the database engine expects to do based on the statistics and metadata of the tables and indexes. An actual plan is generated after the query is executed and shows what the database engine actually did based on the actual data and resources. An actual plan also includes additional information such as actual row counts, execution time, and wait statistics.</p>



<p>By comparing an estimated plan and an actual plan, you can see if there are any discrepancies between what the database engine expected and what it actually did. For example, if the estimated row count is much lower or higher than the actual row count, it might indicate that the statistics are outdated or inaccurate, which can affect the performance and accuracy of the query. You can also see if there are any warnings or errors in the plan that indicate potential problems such as missing indexes, implicit conversions, parameter sniffing, or memory spills.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>In conclusion, a query execution plan is a blueprint that outlines how a DBMS will execute a particular query. A query execution plan is a powerful tool that can help you optimize your queries and improve your database performance. By learning how to read and analyze a query execution plan, you can gain valuable insights into how your queries work and how to make them faster and more efficient.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/what-is-a-query-execution-plan/">What is a query execution plan?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
