<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Miley Cyrus Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/tag/miley-cyrus/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/miley-cyrus/</link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:26:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Miley Cyrus Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/tag/miley-cyrus/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball meaning (song)</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/miley-cyrus-wrecking-ball-meaning-song/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 08:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Songs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Miley Cyrus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wrecking ball]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In this blog post, we will explore the meaning and symbolism of one of Miley Cyrus&#8217;s most iconic songs, &#8220;Wrecking Ball&#8221;. Released in 2013, the song was a huge hit, reaching number one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart and becoming one of the best-selling singles of all time. But what is the song Miley&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/miley-cyrus-wrecking-ball-meaning-song/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball meaning (song)</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/miley-cyrus-wrecking-ball-meaning-song/">Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball meaning (song)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In this blog post, we will explore the meaning and symbolism of one of Miley Cyrus&#8217;s most iconic songs, &#8220;Wrecking Ball&#8221;. Released in 2013, the song was a huge hit, reaching number one on the Billboard Hot 100 chart and becoming one of the best-selling singles of all time. But what is the song Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball meaning? And what does the wrecking ball represent?</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Meaning of Wrecking Ball Miley Cyrus</h2>



<p>According to Miley Cyrus herself, &#8220;Wrecking Ball&#8221; is a song about a strong and passionate love that ended in heartbreak and pain. She said in <a href="https://onairwithryan.iheart.com/featured/ryan-seacrest/content/2018-12-10-miley-cyrus-tells-lol-paddle-boarding-story-it-was-a-signal-for-distress/">an interview</a> with Ryan Seacrest:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;I think the video explains it pretty clearly. It&#8217;s not just about breaking things. It&#8217;s about breaking things that were holding you back. And I had to do that. I had to let go of someone that I loved very much, but it wasn&#8217;t healthy for me anymore.&#8221;</p>
<cite>Miley Cyrus</cite></blockquote>



<p>Some critics and fans have speculated that the song was inspired by Miley Cyrus&#8217;s relationship with actor Liam Hemsworth, whom she dated on and off for several years before getting married in 2018 and divorced in 2020. The song&#8217;s lyrics seem to reflect some of the issues and conflicts that they faced as a couple, such as communication problems, trust issues, and emotional distance. The lyrics suggest that Miley was trying to break down Liam&#8217;s walls and make him open up to her, but she ended up pushing him away instead. She also implies that she still loves him and wants him back, even though they have parted ways .</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Youtube Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball music videos</h2>



<p>The video was controversial and provocative, but it also had a deeper meaning. Miley Cyrus revealed that the song was inspired by Sinead O&#8217;Connor&#8217;s Nothing Compares 2 U, which is another classic ballad about heartbreak and loss. Miley said:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;I wanted to do something that was similar to Sinead O&#8217;Connor&#8217;s video because I felt like it was one of the most honest videos of all time. And I wanted to be honest with myself and with my fans.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<div class="nv-iframe-embed"><iframe title="Miley Cyrus - Wrecking Ball (Official Video)" width="1200" height="675" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/My2FRPA3Gf8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></div>
</div></figure>



<p>The director of the MV was Terry Richardson and it features Miley Cyrus swinging on a giant wrecking ball, wearing nothing but but underwear, white tank top and boots. The video also shows her licking a sledgehammer and smashing walls with it. Although the video shows her crying for love, it also shows her naked, which caused a lot of controversy and criticism at the time. Miley defended her opinions about feminism, sexuality, and artistic expression by saying:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;I think nudity is beautiful and natural and I don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s something to be ashamed of. I think it&#8217;s a way of expressing vulnerability and emotion. And I think it fits perfectly with the song.&#8221;</p>
</blockquote>



<p>Miley said that she wanted to show her emotions without any distractions or filters. She said that the video was not about being sexy or shocking, but about being honest and real, and that the nudity symbolized her honesty and vulnerability. The singer also said that the tears were real, as she was thinking about her ex while filming the video.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">The deeper meaning of <strong>Miley Cyrus song Wrecking Ball about</strong></h2>



<p>The music video also contrasts two different sides of Miley Cyrus: the fierce and rebellious side that swings on the wrecking ball and destroys everything around her, and the fragile and sensitive side that cries and looks into the camera with pain and longing. This contrast reflects Miley Cyrus&#8217;s own transformation as an artist and a person, as she shed her innocent and wholesome image from her Disney days and embraced a more edgy and mature style. The video also shows how Miley Cyrus deals with her emotions: <a href="https://uniqwe.com/it-is-better-to-be-hated-for-what-you-are-than-to-be-loved-for-what-you-are-not-meaning-andre-gides-quote/">by expressing them openly and boldly, even if it means being criticized or misunderstood by others</a>.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large"><img decoding="async" src="https://ichef.bbci.co.uk/news/464/mcs/media/images/70251000/jpg/_70251117_cyrus_oconnor.jpg" alt=""/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Miley Cyrus and Sinead O&#8217;Connor</figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The song is very powerful and emotional, and it showcases Miley Cyrus&#8217; amazing vocal abilities. She sings with passion and intensity, conveying her pain and sorrow. The song&#8217;s haunting melody and raw vocals create a sense of vulnerability and sadness, making it a poignant and memorable ballad. The song also has a catchy chorus that sticks in your head and makes you want to sing along.</p>



<p>The song also shows how Miley Cyrus still loves her ex and can&#8217;t let go of him, even though he hurt her. She sings: &#8220;Don&#8217;t you ever say I just walked away / I will always want you&#8221;, feeling like he wrecked her heart and left her broken and empty. She also cries out for his attention and affection, saying: &#8220;I put you high up in the sky / And now, you&#8217;re not coming down / It slowly turned, you let me burn / And now, we&#8217;re ashes on the ground&#8221;.</p>



<h2 class="wp-block-heading">Conclusion</h2>



<p>&#8220;Wrecking Ball&#8221; is a song that resonates with many people who have gone through a breakup or a heartbreak. It uses the metaphor of the wrecking ball to convey how a relationship can be both destructive and empowering, how love can be both painful and healing, and how a person can be both strong and vulnerable. Others have suggested that it is a commentary on the pressures of fame and the toll that it can take on personal relationships. </p>



<p>Wrecking Ball is a masterpiece of pop music and a testament to Miley Cyrus&#8217; talent and versatility. It&#8217;s one of her best works and one of the most influential songs of our generation. Wrecking Ball is more than just a song. It&#8217;s a statement of empowerment, courage and resilience. It&#8217;s a song that shows how Miley Cyrus transformed from a Disney star to a mature artist who is not afraid to be herself and to express her feelings.</p>



<p>What do you think of &#8220;Wrecking Ball&#8221; by Miley Cyrus? Do you like this song? Do you relate to its meaning? Let us know in the comments below!</p>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/miley-cyrus-wrecking-ball-meaning-song/">Miley Cyrus Wrecking Ball meaning (song)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
