<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<atom:link href="https://uniqwe.com/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/category/uncategorized/</link>
	<description>know and help</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 04:05:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://uniqwe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/cropped-photo1679071723-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Uncategorized Archives - Uniqwe</title>
	<link>https://uniqwe.com/category/uncategorized/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>&#8216;If you were a girl, I would marry you&#8217;, he said</title>
		<link>https://uniqwe.com/if-you-were-a-girl-i-would-marry-you-he-said/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[uniqwe]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 04:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[story]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://uniqwe.com/?p=268</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone! I have a funny story to share with you today. It&#8217;s about something that happened to me when I was in kindergarten. You won&#8217;t believe what a boy said to me back then! So, there was this boy in my class who was very cute and smart. He had blond hair and blue&#8230;&#160;<a href="https://uniqwe.com/if-you-were-a-girl-i-would-marry-you-he-said/" class="" rel="bookmark">Read More &#187;<span class="screen-reader-text">&#8216;If you were a girl, I would marry you&#8217;, he said</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/if-you-were-a-girl-i-would-marry-you-he-said/">&#8216;If you were a girl, I would marry you&#8217;, he said</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hi everyone! I have a funny story to share with you today. It&#8217;s about something that happened to me when I was in kindergarten. You won&#8217;t believe what a boy said to me back then!</p>



<p>So, there was this boy in my class who was very cute and smart. He had blond hair and blue eyes, and he always got good grades. He was also very nice to everyone, especially to me. He would share his snacks with me, help me with my homework, and play with me during recess. He was my best friend and I liked him a lot.</p>



<p>One day, we were sitting together on the swings, talking about our dreams and plans for the future. He said he wanted to be a doctor when he grew up, because he liked to help people. I said I wanted to be a writer, because I liked to tell stories. He smiled and said he liked my stories too. Then he looked at me with a serious expression and said something that made me blush.</p>



<p>He said: &#8220;You know, if you were a girl, I would marry you when we grow up.&#8221;</p>



<p>I was so surprised and confused by his words that I didn&#8217;t know what to say. I mean, I knew I was a boy, and he was a boy too. How could we get married? And why did he say that? Did he like me more than a friend? Did he think I was a girl or want me to be a girl?</p>



<p>I asked him: &#8220;Why do you say that? I&#8217;m not a girl.&#8221;</p>



<p>He shrugged and said: &#8220;I know, but you&#8217;re so nice and sweet and funny. You&#8217;re the best person I know. And you have long hair and pretty eyes. You look like a girl sometimes.&#8221;</p>



<p>I didn&#8217;t know whether to feel flattered or offended by his compliments. I liked him too, but not in that way. And I didn&#8217;t want to look like a girl. I was proud of being a boy:</p>



<p>&#8220;But I don&#8217;t want to be a girl. I like being a boy.&#8221;</p>



<p>He nodded and said: &#8220;That&#8217;s okay. You can be whatever you want to be. I like you anyway.&#8221;</p>



<p>He gave me a hug and a kiss on the cheek, then jumped off the swing and ran away. I was left there, stunned and speechless, with my face burning red.</p>



<p>That was the first time someone told me they would marry me if I were a girl. It was also the last time I saw him, because he moved away soon after that. I never forgot him though. He was my first crush and my first heartbreak.</p>



<p>I wonder what he&#8217;s doing now. Maybe he&#8217;s still a doctor, helping people. Maybe he&#8217;s married to someone who looks like me. I hope he still remembers me too.</p>



<p>Or maybe he&#8217;s reading this blog post right now.</p>



<p>If you are, hi there! It&#8217;s me, your old friend from kindergarten. Do you still want to marry me if I were a girl?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/if-you-were-a-girl-i-would-marry-you-he-said/">&#8216;If you were a girl, I would marry you&#8217;, he said</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://uniqwe.com/">Uniqwe</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
